Curriculum Vitae

Personal information

First name(s) / Surname(s)

Francis Muriithi Mbutei.

Address(es)

P. O. Box 47- 10303, Wang'uru.

Telephone(s)

Mobile: +254 726 254 430

E-mail

Mbuteif@kebs.org Alternate Email /Personal: reithifm@gmail.com

Nationality

Kenyan

Date of birth

30th June, 1987

Gender

Male

About

I'm a registered graduate Mechanical Engineer with 7 years of experience in Oil and Gas. Seeking to leverage my experience in the role of Mechanical Engineer.

Current Work Dates Market Surveillance Officer - Kenya Bureau of Standards.

April 2022- To date.

Previous Work experience

Field Engineer -Baker Hughes Kenya Ltd.

Dates

August 2013 - December 2020

Occupation or position held

Field Engineer (Completions and Wellbore Interventions Department)

Main activities and responsibilities

Design and equipment selection for Total E&P South Africa, Luiperd 1X Project.

Raise Purchase Requisition and Purchase Order and Delivery using SAP and internal Trackers.

Workshop Preparation of Premier Packer for 9.625 Inch Casing.

Disassembling, redress and assembling of Baker Hughes Liner hanger &Wellbore intervention tools.

Field Service hand for Packer Installations on Drill Pipe.

Industry Clients/Projects

- TEPSA Luiperd 1AX. Prepare Liner Hanger and Premier Packer Assemblies 2019-Dec 2020.
- Zarara Oil and Gas, Kenya. Liner Hanger and Completion Equipment Preparation.2018-2019
- EDD Djibouti Prepare and Installation of Mechanical Liner Hanger- March 2019
- Tullow Oil (Liner Hanger installation in Block 10BB Packer installations Onshore Field Operations, Kenya) Feb 2015 - Dec 2017
- Egypt (Kattameya Base. Liner Hanger Equipment Preparation for Bapetco and Rashpetco) Jan 2015
- Saudi Aramco (Liner Hanger and Completion Equipment Preparation at the Base and installation in Harad Field Operations, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia) Feb – May 2014
- BP GOM Workshop preparation for Offshore Jobs, Houma, Louisiana USA -Dec 2013

Name and address of employer

Lean Energy Solutions

Type of business or sector

Energy

Dates

June 2013 - Aug 2013

Occupation or position held

Mechanical Engineer

Main activities and responsibilities

Design, installation and Maintenance of Boilers, Energy Management and Audits, Production of Lean Briquettes from Agro mass waste.

Page 1/2 - Curriculum vitae of Francis Muriithi Mbutei

Education and training

Dates

August 2007 - August 2012

Title of qualification awarded

BSc Mechanical Engineering

Principal subjects/occupational skills covered Engineering Mathematics ,Fluid Mechanics, Engineering Thermo-Dynamics, Mechanics of machines, Material Science, AutoCAD, Communication skills, Management, Workshop practices, Production and

Maintenance

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Kenyatta University, Nairobi Kenya

Qualification for Hydraulic Set Packers - Virtual Training- 2020

Fishing Services for Geothermal Operations- Kengen, Naivasha -May 2019 Sub-Surface Safety Systems Training -Broken Arrow, Oklahoma. May, 2018

Packer Systems Training- EHEC, Dubai Feb 2014

Personal skills and competences

Proficient in Microsoft office software, SAP software, .

Other language(s) Self-assessment Proficient in English, Swahili

Social skills and competencies

Team work, Integrity, Highly Adaptable to different working environments, Excellent

interpersonal Skills, analytical and technically competent.

Referees

Catherine Wanyonyi Robin Shake

Email: wanyonyic@kebs.org Email: Shaker@kebs.org

Phone: +254720338876 Phone: +254728554112